Guide to the Ghassem Ghani collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- SERIES II
  - 198. Kamran Mirza to Rafi: An invitation to dinner. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 199. Sepahdar to Rafi: In reply to Rafi's complaint about the telephone conditions between Tehran and Te (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 200. Sepahsalar to Rafi expressing condolences on the death of Shariet Madar. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 201. General Abdullarh Khan Tahmasebi addressee unknown. Concerning slanderous rumors about Mahmud Khan. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 202. Ein-od-Dowleh to Rafi: Expressing his thanks for the termination of his affairs with the bank. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 203. Adl-ol-Mulk to Rafi: A friendly letter. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 204. Asef-od-Dowleh Salehi to Rafi: Complaining of his affairs and the lack of concern of the members of the government for him. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 205. Abdullah Khan Amir Tahmasebi to Rafi: Concerning the steps taken for the construction of roads and general improvements in Azerbaijan. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 206. Rules and regulations of the Cabinet, dated Rajab 1314 A.H., signed by Muzaffar-ed-Din Shah. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 207. Asef-od-Dowleh to addressee unknown. Complaining that no one is concerned about him. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 208. A printed announcement by Kuchek Khan concerning the appointment of Khalu Qurban as his deputy and as the chief of a detachment of the Red Army of the Republic (Rise of Kuchek Khan in Mazanderan against the central government.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 209. Mirza Mohammad Khan Sepahsalar to Mirza Aqa Khan: Explaining the demands of Mirza Mohammad Ali Kahn for 1200 tumans. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 210. The decision of the Cabinet, signed by Mozaffar-ed-Din Shah: Concerning the export of rice from Gilan, to Europe. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 211. A piece of handwriting of Qavam-od-Dowleh: Concerning the mills of Tarasht. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 212. Sahib Ekltiar to Kamran Mirza: An invitation to a party. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 213. An order for the appointment of Mohammad Taher Mirza to Governorship of Qarejeh Dagh, sealed by Mirza Said Khan, minister of foreign affairs, dated Rabi-os-Sani, 1262. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 214. The handwriting of Amin-od-Dowleh, concerning the establishment of a special assembly named the assembly of nobles, signed by Mozaffar-ed-Din Shah. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 215. Mohammad Hasan Mirza Valiahd (Crown Prince) to Saheb EkhtiÄr 4 Saratan (Cancer) 1303 A.H., complaining of dizziness and requesting his speedy return. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 216. Haj Sheykh Abd-al-Karim, to Rafi: A note of thanks. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 217. Same to Same. Asking to transmit a message to the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 218. Same to Same. Note of greetings. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 219. Ab-ol Hasan Musavi-al EsfÄhÄni to Rafi: Answer to two questions in regard to canon law. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 220. Modarres to Rafi: 19 Jamadi-al-ulÄ1242, concerning the situation in KÄshÄn and the likelihood of dissorders in connection with elections. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 221. DÄvar to Mowlavi (from Europe), February 14, 1911, complaining about conditions in Iran. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 222. Esmail Momtaz al-Dowleh to Mowlevi, 14 Day 1309, concerning sums of money owed him. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 223. DÄvar to Mowlavi (from Europe) November 3, 1912. Criticism of conditions in Iran. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 224. Order of Mozaffar ed-Din Mirza, Heir to the Throne, to Amid- od-Dowleh Governor of Khoi and Salmas. Shavval 1296. Concerning a local rebel. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 225. Mirza Hasan Safi All Shah to (unknown) Greetings. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 226. French Ambassador in Constantinople to Mozaffar ed-Din Shah (Translation), congratulating him upon his accession to the throne. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 227. Haj Sheykh MortezÄ Ashtiani to (unknown) Greetings. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 228. Fakhr-od-Dowleh ShirÄzi to (unknown) Greetings (Excellent example of Persian calligraphy.) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 229. Seykh Fazlollah Nuri to (unknown) Concerning the arrest of a merchant In Mashad and a request for his release. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 230. Sheykh al-Eraqeyn to (unknown) Congratulations. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 231. Haj Mirza HedÄyat Javaheri to (unknown) requesting the return of a ring. On the margin autograph of Mirza Said Khan, Minister of Foreign Affairs. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 232. ZorriÄsateyn Shirazi to (unknown) requesting the return of a ring. On the margin autograph of Mirza Said Khan, Minister of Foreign Affairs. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 233. Mirza Hashem Ashtiani to (unknown) Invitation to dinner. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 234. Haj Seyyed Abol Qasem KÄshÄni to (unknown), recommending Seyyed Abdol Karim the Mojtahed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 235: Mirza Lotf Ali Sadr ol-AfÄzel to (unknown), note of thanks. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 236. Shariat MadÄr Rashti to (unknown) Note of thanks. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 237. Unknown to unknown. On the margin autograph of Adib PashÄvari, recommending the hiring of Sheykh Ali in the library. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 238. Haj Abol Hasan Mirza Sheykh al-Rais from Shiraz to Tehran to (unknown) informing his correspondent of the dispatch of 25 volumes of his books. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 239. Haj Sheykh Abdol Karim, Head of the Qom Learned Society (clerical) to (unknown) Recommending Ali Borjuerdi. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 240. Haj Sheykh Mehdi Shams ol-OlamÄto (unknown) Note of thanks. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 241. AgÄ ZiÄ ArÄki to (unknown) thanking the Ministry of Education. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 242. Hojjat ol-EslÄm HÄj AgÄli Akbar Borujerdi to (unknown), concerning an order of the Prime Minister. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 243. HÄj Sheykh Mohammad Mazandarani from Karbela to (unknown), concerning royal gifts to be sent to Haydarabad. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 244. EmÄm Jom'e of ZanjÄn to (unknown), recommending Ezz-od-Din. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 245. Mirza Mohammad Bager Guardian of the Shrine at Qom to (unknown), 18 Day 1317. Greetings. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 246. HÄj AgÄ JamÄl EsfahÄni (VÄez) to (unknown). Greetings and complaints about ill health. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 247. Letter by unknown author, on the margin the handwriting of Haji Mirza Hadi Dowlet Abad: Concerning the sale somebody's estate. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 248. Syyid Hasan Modarres to (unknown) prince Regretting that misunderstanding has occurred. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 249. Amin-os-Soltan (chancellor) to the Persian Embassy in Turkey. Dated 1309 A.H. Concerning Jamal-ed-Din and his expulsion from Turkey. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 250. Amin-os-Soltan to the Persian embassy in Turkey, dated 1309, A.H. Concerning the demand of subscription fees to Al-Ahram (edited in Egypt.) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 251. Mohammad Ibrahim Alam Amir Shoukat-ol-Molk to Dr. Ghani--dated 1321 (solar year)--Greetings. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 252. Syyid Mohammad Behbehan? to Dr. Ghani. Recommending Dr. Ehsan. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 253. Abdol Mohammad Khan to unknown. Asking salary to be sent to Kurdestan. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 254. Mohammad Shah to Qahraman Mirza dated 1257 A.H. Concerning removal of Mohammad Rahim Mirza. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 255. Bill of expenditure of the personnel of the stable and the artillery of Khorasam signed by Hesam-os-Soltaneh. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 256. Andalib-od-Dowleh to Amin-od-Dowleh concerning the dispatch of letters by Aqa Ali. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 257. Receipt of membership dues received by the judicial society, (receipt in the name of Momayezol-Mamadek). (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 258. The same. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 259. Mokhber-os-Soltaneh to Dr. Ghani--Concerning the building donated for hospital use. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 260. Amir-Shoukat-al-Molk Alam to Dr. Ghani--Sending saffron. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 261. Mo'tamen-ol-Molk Pir Nia to Dr. Ghani. Thanking the doctor for the book about Sufism. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- SERIES III
  - 1. Mirza Hoseyn Khan Moshir-od-Dowleh to Nasir-od-Dowleh (Chancellor): Sending the papers approved by the Shah for execution. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 2. Same to Same. Concerning his health, and a letter to Ataullah Khan. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 3. Same to Same. Sending a few telegrams signed by the Shah. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 4. Same to Same. Inviting Nasir-od-Dowleh to his garden. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 5. Same to Same. Concerning the answer to the telegram and Saheb Divan's telegram. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 6. Same to Same. Concerning the appointment of a functionary to Astrabad. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 7. Same to Same. Concerning personal relations. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 8. Same to Same. Concerning a telegram received from Mo'tamed-od-Dowleh. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 9. Same to Same. Concerning personal relations. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 10. Same to Same. Concerning Nasir-od-Dowleh's departure for Mekka. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 11. Same to Same. Concerning personal relations. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 12. Same to Same. Concerning letters from Khorasan. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 13. Same to Same. Concerning Amin Lashkar and his proposition. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 14. Same to Same. Concerning personal relations. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 15. Same to Same. Concerning the budget of Khorasan. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 16. Same to Same. Concerning personal relations and Nasir-od-Dowleh's view of Tukkomen. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 17. Same to Same. Concerning personal relations. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 18. Same to Same. Concerning the budget of Astrahad. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 19. Same to Same. Concerning Nasir-od-Dowleh's trip. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 20. Same to Same. Concerning Nasir-od-Dowleh's trip to Mekka. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 21. Same to Same. Expressing happiness for Nasir-od-Dowleh's well being. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 22. Same to Same. Concerning personal relations. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 23. Same to Same. Informing Nasir-od-Dowleh that he is his representative in matters concerning Khorasen, Fars and Astrabad. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 24. Same to Same. Concerning Shah's visit to his garden. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 25. Same to Same. Concerning personal relations. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 26. Same to Same. Sending Ma'tamed-od-Dowleh's telegram. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 27. Mirza Hoseyn Khan Moshir-od-Dowleh to Nasir-od-Dowleh (Chancellor): Concerning the list of the members of the council. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 28. Same to Same. Concerning Mo'tamed-ol-Molk's salary. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 29. Same to Same. Instructions concerning current matters. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 30. Same to Same. Concerning the receipt of the salary. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 31. Same to Same. Concerning personal relations. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 32. Same to Same. Concerning routine matters. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 33. Same to Same. Concerning personal matters. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 34. Same to Same. Concerning intimate relations. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 35. Telegram to the Chancellor: Concerning monetary matters. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 36. Farhad Mirza's telegram to Moshir-od-Dowleh (Chancellor) Concerning the occupation of the Dehmarv fortress by the government forces. On the back pages handwriting of Naser-od-Din Shah dated 1294 A.H.--Commending Farhad Mirza for his victory and ordering him to destroy all the inhabitants of the fortress. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 37. Nasir-od-Dowleh to Moshir-od-Dowleh Concerning the sending of the salary. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 38. Same to Same. Sending the draft of a telegram. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 39. Same to Same. Concerning a telegram to Astrabad. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 40. Same to Same. Concerning current affairs. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 41. Same to Same. Concerning the case of the so called Sartib. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 42. Same to Same. Concerning the functions of the ministry. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 43. Same to Same. Concerning army expenditures (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 44. Same to Same. Concerning Mulla, Kazem's brother's claims. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 45. Same to Same. Concerning the settlement of Motamed-od-Dowleh's accounts. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 46. Same to Same. Sending a prince's letter. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 47. Same to Same. Concerning personal matters. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 48. Same to Same. Concerning Haji Mirza Naghi's salary. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 49. Same to Same. Concerning personal matters. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 50. Same to Same. Concerning General Haj Qulam Hosein's claim. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 51. Nasir-od-Dowleh to Moshir-od-Dowleh (Chancellor): Resignation from government service and proposal to go on pilgrimage to Mecca. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 52. Same to Same. Information regarding tariff rates on gold and silver bullion. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 53. Unknown to Mirza Hoseyn Khan Moshir od-Dowleh. Discrepancies in accounts kept by two government officials. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 54. Memorandum (unsigned, undated) in regard to the tariff on gold and silver. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 55. Nasir-od-Dowleh to Mirza Hoseyn Khan Moshir od-Dowleh: Regarding current administrative affairs. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 56. Mirza Hoseyn Khan Moshir od-Dowleh to unknown: Personal note. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 57. Nasir od-Dowleh to Moshir od-Dowleh: Current administrative problems. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 58. Report to Naser-ed-Din Shah (unsigned) Regarding travel expenses of Soleyman Khan Saheb EkhtiÄr. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 59. List of items submitted by Nasir od-Dowleh to Moshir od-Dowleh in connection with the army's needs in KhorÄsÄn. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 60. Ministry of Commerce and Agriculture. Report to Naser ed-Din Shah (undated) concerning the trip of Soleyma. Khan Saheb EkhtiÄr to the Khorasan frontier. (Autographed by the Shah on the margin.) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 61. Account of Soleyman Khan Saheb Ekhtiar: Expenses. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 62. Telegraphic draft of a sum of money from Tehran to Mashhad (1301 A.H.) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 63. Council of Ministers to Naser ed-Din Shah regarding the pay of Sõleyman Khan (undated). (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 64. Imperial decree of Naser ed-Din Shah to Amin ol-Molk, TushgÄn IL 96. Regarding registrations of deaths. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 65. Nasir od-Dowleh to Naser ed Din Shah: Regarding relations between Mo'tamed od-Dowleh and Zelles-Soleten (undated) Marginal note in Shah's hand. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 66. Moin od-Dowleh to Nasir od-Dowleh (undated): Greetings. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 67. Zell-es-Soltan to Nasir od-Dowleh Concerning the grave of Jal al-od-Dowleh in Mashhad. (Undated) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 68. Zell-es-Soltan to Nasir od-Dowleh Concerning Nasir's trip to Mashhad (undated) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 69. Unknown to Nasir od-Dowleh: Private matters (a bet). (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 70. Unknown to Nasir od-Dowleh (?) Private matters. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 71. Naser ed-Din Shah to Mirza Hoseyn Khan Moshir od-Dowleh Sepahsalar (undated) Requesting information on political matters between Russia and Turkey from his Minister at St. Petersburg. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 72. Same to Same. Ordering an official to write more clearly. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 73. Same to Same. Concerning storage of guns. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 74. Same to Same. Concerning Kurdestan taxes. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 75. Same to Same. Dispatch of 10 horsemen to Qom to put down disorders. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 76. Mo'tamed od-Dowleh, Shiraz, to Mirza Hoseyn Khan Moshir-od-Dowleh Sepahsalar, Tehran 27 Ramazan 1293 A.H. Conquest of the fortress of Shahriari. In the margin Shah's autograph, expressing his approbation. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 77. Mirza Hoseyn Khan Moshir od-Dowleh Sepahsalar to Naser ed-Din Shah Concerning Mo'tamed's telegram from Shiraz. In the margin the Shah's autograph. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 78. Unknown, Tabriz, to Mirza Hoseyn KhÄn Moshir od-Dowleh Sepahsalar, Tehran. Telegram, coded, undated. Concerning the Russo-Turkish War and the number of Persian forces on the borders. In margin orders of the Shah in regard to numbers of troops to be maintained. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 79. Naser ed-Din Shah to Mirza Hoseyn KhÄn Moshir od-Dowleh Sepehsaler Concerning the letters of Hesan os-Soltaneh. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 80. HesÄm os-Saltaneh, KermÄn Shah, to Mirza Hoseyn KhÄn Moshi[rtilde]-od-Dowleh, Telegram, 26 Rabi-ol-Avval 1294 A.H. Concerning the inability of some troops to transfer without first receiving their pay. In the margin Shah's resolution to pay the men. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 81. Unknown from Tabriz to Mirza Hoseyn Khan Moshir od-Dowleh, telegram, 26 Rabi ol-Avval 1294 A.H. In regard to the pay of the cabalry in Azerbarijan. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 82. MirzÄ Hoseyn KhÄn Moshir od-Dowleh Sepahsalar to NÄser ed Din Shah. (undated) Concerning meeting with Russian Minister on the problem of Persian Kurds, their possible participation in the Russo-Turkish War, and Persia's preventive measures. In the margin Shah's order to assure Russians that Kurds will not be allowed to aid the Turks. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 83. Same to Same. Concerning a pension for Ehtesham ol-Molk family. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- A The Letters of Am?r Kabir from No. 1 to 210., Series III
  - 1. Amir Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Concerning the expenses of the kitchen of the late Mohammad Shah. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 2. Same to Same. Concerning the time of audience. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 3. Same to Same. Concerning the audience of the British minister with the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 4. Same to Same. Thanking the Shah for his kind letter. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 5. Same to Same. Informing Shah about his work. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 6. Same to Same. Asking Shah to inform him in case the Shah's doctor will will be changed. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 7. Same to Same. Asking for time of audience. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 8. Same to Same. Concerning the arrival of Russian envoy. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 9. Same to Same. Concerning the arrival of the British envoy. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 10. Same to Same. Concerning information to the Shah of the receipt of his letter in which he expressed his desire to go horseback riding. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 11. Amir Kabir to (unknown) Concerning audience given by Shah. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 12. Amir Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah Concerning the regiment of Khamseh. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 13. Same to Same. Concerning the book about military matters. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 14. Same to Same. Concerning the negotiations with the Minister. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 15. Same to Same. Complaining about ill health. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 16. Same to Same. Concerning the negotiations with Qarib Saheb and report of the ill humor of Shah's mother. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 17. Same to Same. Concerning his health. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 18. Same to Same. Expressing joy at the good health of the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 19. Same to Same. Concerning his health. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 20. Same to Same. Asking whether it is true that the Shah is coming to the Mosque. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 21. Same to Same. Concerning the expenses of the religious ceremony and horse racing. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 22. Same to Same. Concerning the military drill. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 23. Same to Same. Concerning the marriage of Azim Agha. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 24. Amir Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Concerning the health of the Crown Prince; and expressing concern about his entourage. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 25. Same to Same. Informing Shah that he is busy and cannot accompany him for riding. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 26. Same to Same. Informing the Shah that he cannot see him because of headache and because he is busy negotiating with the Turkish representative. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 27. Same to Same. Concerning some known person. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 28. Same to Same. Concerning the letter which was not delivered to Mirza Mohammad Ali Khan. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 29. Same to Same. Informing Shah that he will talk with Haji Beglar Beg? about Yahya Khan. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 30. Same to Same. Concerning the review of the cavalry of tribes. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 31. Same to Same. Concerning the invitation or the correspondence with the minister. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 32. Same to Same. Sending some letters to the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 33. Same to Same. Sending the letter from the mayor of Ghandhar to Shah. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 34. Same to Same. Sending some letters to Shah for his approval. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 35. Same to Same. Informing the Shah about his discussions with the Graf (Count). (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 36. Same to Same. Sending some letters received from Tabr?z for the Shah's perusal. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 37. Same to Same. Introducing Mohammad Hansan to the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 38. Same to Same. Explaining the reason of his absence from Shah's court. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 39. Same to Same. Concerning Hmazeh Mirza's courier (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 40. Same to Same. Announcing that the soldiers will be ready in the afternoon. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 41. Same to Same. Some letters are sent to the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 42. Same to Same. Concerning the Shah's horse riding. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 43. Same to Same. Concerning the departure of the tribe. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 44. Same to Same. Concerning Haji Ali Khan. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 45. Same to Same. Sending some letters for approval. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 46. Am?r Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Informing the Shah that he is busy with accounting work. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 47. Same to Same. Reporting the current news of the day. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 48. Same to Same. Suggesting that Shah order the governors to submit reports. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 49. Same to Same. Concerning the audience. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 50. Same to Same. Sending the letter from the Russian minister to the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 51. Same to Same. Reporting the current news of the day. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 52. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 53. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 54. Same to Same. Sending 600 tumans for the Harem servants. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 55. Same to Same. Sending some letters for the Shah to see. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 56. Same to Same. Concerning an audience with the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 57. Same to Same. Concerning Fazlollah Khan Garagozlu and his departure to Phars. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 58. Same to Same. Reporting current activities and affairs of the country. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 59. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 60. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 61. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 62. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 63. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 64. Same to Same. Telling the Shah that he is moving the army in Astarabad from one place to another. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 65. Same to Same. Telling the Shah that he is reading the letters from Khorasan. Also concerning the financial disagreements between Khan Khanan and Mahd Oliya (Shah's mother.) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 66. Same to Same. A letter from Russian Minister requesting an audience with the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 67. Same to Same. Concerning the documents of the late Amir which are presently in the hands of Haji. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 68. Same to Same. Saying that there is nothing new, and that he is awaiting the arrival of the Russian envoy. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 69. Amir Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Concerning Shah's horseback riding. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 70. Same to Same. Presenting two letters which have been written to the representatives of two great countries. (Russia and England). (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 71. Same to Same. Telling the Shah that the certain person had come and told him about Russia and Rume (Turkey). He will report it in detail later. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 72. Same to Same, Complaining that he has heard that the Shah had said unkind things about him. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 73. Same to Same. Concerning his meetings with the Russian minister. (Box 1, Folder 13)